<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<SPDXLicenseCollection xmlns="http://www.spdx.org/license">
  <exception licenseId="AGPL-3.0-API-call-exception" name="AGPL 3.0 API Call Exception">
    <crossRef>https://github.com/agpl-3-0-api-call-exception/license-text/blob/1.0/agpl-3.0-api-call-exception.txt</crossRef>
    <notes>Designed to be used with AGPL-3.0 -only</notes>
    <text>
    <titleText>
      AGPL 3.0 API Call Exception
    </titleText>

    <p>
      As a special exception, using the interfaces contained in the files listed
      in `excepted.api` included in the source distribution (the “Excepted API”)
      shall not, by itself, cause the calling code to be subject to the GNU
      Affero General Public License v3.0.
    </p>

    <p>For the avoidance of doubt:</p>
    <list>
      <item>
        The file `excepted.api` is the sole authoritative specification of which
        source files define the Excepted API. The interfaces contained in those
        files are the only ones covered by this exception.
      </item>
      <item>
        This exception applies only to calling, compiling against, or linking
        against the interfaces contained in the files listed in `excepted.api`.
        It does not apply to direct use of any other parts of the work not
        listed in the `excepted.api` file.
      </item>
      <item>
        Implementation details, including any transitive code, libraries, or
        elements used internally to satisfy calls to the Excepted API, do not
        extend this exception to any part of the work not listed in the
        `excepted.api` file.
      </item>
      <item>
        Merely compiling against, linking against, or invoking the Excepted API,
        and the fact that such actions may require the work to access or load
        other elements, shall not by itself be considered creation of a derivative
        work by the caller.
      </item>
      <item>
        This exception does not grant permission to copy, modify, or distribute
        any file except as otherwise permitted under the GNU Affero General Public
        License v3.0.
      </item>
    </list>
  </text>
  </exception>
</SPDXLicenseCollection>

